{"test_questions": [[{"question": "1 kg wt in gravitational unit equals", "opta": "8.9 N in SI system", "optb": "9.8 N in SI system", "optc": "4.5 N in SI system", "optd": "5.4 N in SI system.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To convert the units of M.K.S. to units of S.I., a factor 9.80665 is used for", "opta": "mass", "optb": "force", "optc": "work energy", "optd": "power", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "SI unit for the surface tension, is", "opta": "kg/m3", "optb": "kg/m2", "optc": "kg/m", "optd": "N/m", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The basic quantity in the International system of units, is", "opta": "length and mass", "optb": "time and temperature", "optc": "mole and light intensity", "optd": "electric current", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Intensity of electric current is expressed in", "opta": "volts", "optb": "watts", "optc": "amperes", "optd": "joules.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One Netwon force equals", "opta": "105 dynes", "optb": "104 dynes", "optc": "103 dynes", "optd": "102 dynes", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In S.I. system, the symbol for density is", "opta": "N/m3", "optb": "kg/m3", "optc": "m3/s", "optd": "kg", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "1 N force = 0.10197 kgf", "optb": "1 kgf = 9.80665 N", "optc": "1 kgf/cm2 = 98.0665 kN/m2", "optd": "1 atm = 101.325 kN/m2", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The thickness of a micron, is", "opta": "10-3 m", "optb": "10-6 m", "optc": "10-9 m", "optd": "10-12 m", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The fundamental units in S.I. system, are the same as that of", "opta": "C.G.S. units", "optb": "F.P.S. units", "optc": "M.K.S. units", "optd": "None of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "In S.I. system, pressure is expressed in N/m2", "optb": "In S.I. system, surface tension is expressed in Newton per metre", "optc": "In S.I. system, force is expressed in Newtons", "optd": "In S.I. system, power is expressed in watts", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "100 kN/m2 pressure is equal to", "opta": "1 atm", "optb": "1 bar", "optc": "1 m bar", "optd": "1 mm Hg", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The solid angles are measured in", "opta": "degrees", "optb": "grades", "optc": "radians", "optd": "steradians.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "10-12, is called", "opta": "Terra", "optb": "pico", "optc": "Giga", "optd": "Mega", "opte": "None of these.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "The units of moment of inertia of a plane area, depends upon the units of the area and the length", "optb": "The moment of inertia is expressed in m4 if the area is in square metres and the length is also in metres", "optc": "The moment of inertia is expressed in cm4 if the area is in square centimetres and the length in centimetres", "optd": "The moment of inertia is expressed in mm4 if the area is in square millimetres and the length in millimetres", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The intensity of pressure at a certain place is 1 kg (f)/m2, the intensity of pressur e in SI units will be", "opta": "47.88 N/m2", "optb": "9.81 N/m2", "optc": "4.882 N/m2", "optd": "0.07013 N/m2", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If \u03b1 is the angular acceleration of a body of moment of inertia I, the torque is", "opta": "I2 \u03b1", "optb": "I \u03b1", "optc": "I/\u03b1", "optd": "I2/\u03b1", "opte": "I \u03b11/2", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In SI units, moment is expressed as", "opta": "kg-m", "optb": "kg-cm", "optc": "kg-mm", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Angular acceleration is expressed as", "opta": "m/s2", "optb": "w/s2", "optc": "rad/s2", "optd": "rad/s", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One Newton force produces an acceleration of", "opta": "1 cm/sec2 while acting on a body of 1 gm mass", "optb": "1 cm/sec2 while acting on a body of 1 kg mass", "optc": "1 m/sec2 while acting on a body of 1 kg mass", "optd": "1 m/sec2 while acting on a body of 1 gm mass.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Hertz (Hz) is used to express", "opta": "Luminous intensity", "optb": "electric current intensity", "optc": "power", "optd": "frequency.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Candela (Cd) is used to express", "opta": "luminous intensity", "optb": "electric current intensity", "optc": "power", "optd": "frequency.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The unit kg/m3 is used for", "opta": "force", "optb": "density", "optc": "volume", "optd": "pressure.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The fundamental units in S.I. System are :", "opta": "Centimetre, gram, second", "optb": "Foot, pound, second", "optc": "Metre, kilogram, second", "optd": "Kilometre, kilogram, minute", "opte": "None of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The bar used for defining the standard metre at the International office of weights and measures at Sevres near Paris, is composed of", "opta": "50% platinum and 50% iridium", "optb": "60% platinum and 40% iridium", "optc": "70% platinum and 30% iridium", "optd": "80% platinum and 20% iridium", "opte": "90% platinum and 10% iridium", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "m2/s is used in S.I. system for", "opta": "Surface tension", "optb": "Kinematic viscosity", "optc": "Pressure", "optd": "Power.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The S.I. unit of Modulus of elasticity is", "opta": "Newton/m2", "optb": "Newton/cm2", "optc": "Newton/mm2", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One Newton is equivalent to", "opta": "0.10197 kgf", "optb": "0.20197 kgf", "optc": "9.80665 kgf", "optd": "0.97125 kgf", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Joule or Newton metric is used for", "opta": "Work", "optb": "Torque", "optc": "Energy", "optd": "All the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Stress in SI units is expressed in", "opta": "kg per sq cm", "optb": "kg per sq mm", "optc": "Newton per sq mm", "optd": "Newton per sq cm", "opte": "Newton per sq m", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In S.I. system, symbol for the specific weight is", "opta": "kg/m3", "optb": "N/m3", "optc": "N/m2", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The SI unit of the force is", "opta": "Newton", "optb": "Kilogrames", "optc": "Joule", "optd": "Erg", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In SI system, the unit of temperature, is", "opta": "Degree centigrade", "optb": "Degree Celsius", "optc": "Kelvin", "optd": "Degree Fahrenheit.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "N-s/m2 is used in S.I. system for", "opta": "Kinematic viscosity", "optb": "Dynamic viscosity", "optc": "Mass density", "optd": "Weight density.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Basic unit of thermodynamic temperature, is", "opta": "degree fahrenheit", "optb": "degree centigrade", "optc": "degree kelvin", "optd": "degree absolute.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}